(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-06T22:31:42.882354",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
HAPPY MUSIC
どうかし てる また 同じ シャツ を
Something's wrong with me, searching for that same shirt again
いない はず の 人込み に 捜し てた
among the crowd where you couldn't possibly be.
だれ と いて も 何 を 話し ても
No matter who I'm with or what we talk about,
映る すべて ヤダ また かさねて いる
everything I see, oh no, I end up projecting you onto it again.
名前 しか 知らない なのに ね こんなに
I only know your name, yet why does it
気になる の...... これって もしかして
occupy my mind so much? Could this possibly be...
ほら たった今 あたし の なかで
Look, right now, deep inside of me,
響く よ ハッピー ミュージック
happy music is echoing out!
運命 の 針 を 胸 に 落として 奏でる
Dropping the needle of fate onto my heart, I play it.
大事 な 日 も まじめて な 時 も
Whether on important days or serious times,
手加減 なし の パワー プレイ
it's a relentless power play!
誰 より も 先 あなた を 見つけ たくて
Wanting to find you before anyone else does...
ダーリン 今度 も あの シャツ きて きて
Darling, please wear that same shirt next time too!
こんぬいー！ホロライブ3期生の不知火フレアです！
Kon-nui! I'm Shiranui Flare from Hololive Gen 3!
はい！
Hi!
この度は不知火フレア2026 BEMANI楽曲3Dライブ、始まりましたー！
The Shiranui Flare 2026 BEMANI Song 3D Live has officially begun!
1曲目、ハッピーミュージック、ゲーム尺で今回お届けさせていただきましたが、どうでしたか？
For the first song, I performed "Happy Music" in its game-size version. How was it?
今回この衣装は、ポエットちゃんに寄せてみて
This time, I styled this outfit to look like Poet-chan,
ちょっと天使っぽい感じにさせていただきました。ハッピーミュージック大好きな楽曲なので、今回歌わせていただきました。
giving it a bit of an angelic vibe. Since I love "Happy Music" so much, I got to sing it!
今回はですね、タイトルにもあるように、BEMANI楽曲ライブとなっております。
As you can see from the title, this is a BEMANI song live concert.
全部BEMANI楽曲で構成させていただきました！
The entire setlist consists of BEMANI songs!
コナミさんにね、この熱い気持ちを一方的にちょっとお伝えさせていただいたら、
I unilaterally shared my passion with Konami,
全面的にですね、ご協力してくださいまして、
and they were incredibly cooperative and supportive!
なんとですね、見てください！デデン！今回ステージすごいんですよ！
And check this out! Ta-da! The stage is amazing!
これですね、コナミさんから素材をお借りさせていただきまして、
For this stage, we actually borrowed official assets from Konami!
全部、ご用意していただいたりとかしまして。
They prepared everything for us.
めちゃめちゃ可愛い！フレアがポップン派なので、
It's so cute! Since I'm a Pop'n Music fan,
だいたいポップンなんですけど、
it's mostly themed around Pop'n,
DDRとか、下にあるこのキーボードは、
but we also have DDR, and this keyboard at the bottom...
ノスタルジアなのか、それともキーボードマニアなのか、どっちなんだいみたいなところですけど。
Is it Nostalgia, or is it Keyboardmania? Which one is it?
こんな感じで、色々、ここもサウンドボルテックスみたいな感じで、
But anyway, with elements like Sound Voltex here as well,
すごいBEMANI要素を詰め詰めにしたステージになりました！
we've put together a stage packed with BEMANI elements!
本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
ご協力いただきまして、ありがとうございました。
Thank you so much for your cooperation.
これは完全にフレアのやりたい放題みたいなライブになっております。
This live show is basically me doing whatever I want!
でもですね、これが結果的にとっても嬉しいお知らせに繋がるかもしれない、
But you know, this might actually lead to some very happy news...
繋がらないかもしれない。それはちょっと今後のお楽しみに、ということで。
Or maybe not. Look forward to finding out in the future!
ハッシュタグは「#不知火フレア生誕祭2026」でございます！
The hashtag is #ShiranuiFlareBirthday2026!
こちらでですね、スクショとか、ポストとか、色々してもらえると嬉しいです。
I'd be so happy if you could share screenshots and posts using it!
この後どんな曲が出てくるのかは、
The songs coming up next
完全にフレアの好みとか、独断と偏見で選んでるので、
were chosen entirely based on my own personal bias and preferences,
皆様楽しみにしながら、待っててもらえたら嬉しいです。
so I hope you all look forward to them!
知らない方も「あ、こんな曲があるんだ」と知ってもらえたら嬉しいなと思います。
Even if you don't know the songs, I hope you can discover them today.
「明日はポップンしに行こう」とか、
I hope this makes you want to go play Pop'n tomorrow,
「サウンドボルテックスしに行こう」とかいう気持ちになってくれたら嬉しいので、
or play Sound Voltex. I'll be very happy.
楽しみにしててください！
Please look forward to it!
最後まで見てくれないと、ちょっと泣いちゃうかも。
If you don't watch until the end, I might cry.
シクシク、エンエン。チラ。エンエン、泣いちゃうかも！
*Sob, sob, cry, cry*... Peek... *Wah!* I might cry!
ナ・カ・ナ・イ・デ
Don't cry...
本当の孤独も知らない
You don't even know what true loneliness is.
まだ淡い花びらに
Still on the pale petals,
涙の粒 抱えたまま...
holding onto drops of tears...
Pink Rose
[Song: Pink Rose]
ah さわらないで
Ah, please don't touch me.
暖かなその手は
That warm hand of yours
わたしのすべて狂わす
drives all of me mad.
ne 許さないで
Oh, please don't forgive me.
傷口を押さえて
Holding down the wound,
微笑んでる あなたがいる
there you are, smiling.
もう 帰れないね
We can never go back now.
堕ちてゆく時の 甘い香り
The sweet fragrance of falling time,
繰り返すたびに ひどくなる
grows stronger with each repetition.
ダ・キ・シ・メ・テ
Hold me close...
いまだけ好きだってフリして
Just for now, pretend that you love me.
たった ひとつだけなら
If there is only one thing,
ぜんぶ ぜんぶ いらない
I don't need any of it.
ナ・カ・ナ・イ・デ
Don't cry...
本当の孤独も知らない
You don't even know what true loneliness is.
まだ淡い花びらに
Still on the pale petals,
涙の粒 抱えたまま
holding onto drops of tears...
ah 急がないで
Ah, please don't rush.
真実なんか ほら
See, things like the truth
どこにも落ちてないでしょ
aren't fallen anywhere.
ne 見つめないで
Oh, please don't stare at me.
やさしいまなざしを
With those gentle eyes.
憎んでいる？ 求めている？
Are you hating me? Or desiring me?
もう わからなくて
I just don't know anymore.
キスするときの わたしの顔
My face when we kiss...
あたしの顔
...my face,
もっときれいに 見せたいだけ
I just want to show you a more beautiful side of it.
抱きしめて いつでも かわいいフリして
Hold me close, and I'll always pretend to be cute.
真っ赤に色づく実を ずっとずっと待ってる
I'll always, always wait for the fruit to turn deep red.
泣かないで 本当の自分も知らずに
Don't cry, without even knowing your true self...
まだ淡い花びらに 夢の重さ抱えたまま
With the weight of dreams held in the pale petals.
堕ちてゆく時の 甘い香り
The sweet fragrance of when we fall...
繰り返すたびに ひどくなる
It grows stronger every time we repeat it.
抱きしめて 今だけ 好きだってフリして
Hold me close, just pretend to love me for now.
たったひとつだけなら 全部全部いらない
If it's just one thing, then I don't need any of it.
Bloomin' like a Rose 本当の孤独も知らない
Bloomin' like a Rose, without even knowing true loneliness...
まだ淡い花びらに 涙の粒抱えたまま
With teardrops held in the pale petals.
あともう３センチ
Just three more centimeters...
キミのくちびるまで
until my lips reach yours.
妄想うずまく イカした夢はなぜか
For some reason, this cool dream swirling with delusions
これからってトコで いつも覚める
always ends right when it's getting good.
わずかに10センチ
A mere ten centimeters...
伸ばす腕 むなしく
stretching my arm in vain.
シャット 閉まる扉 ホームに独り キミと
The doors shut close, leaving me alone on the platform with you.
ガラス越しに 目と目が合う あぁ
Our eyes meet through the glass window, ah...
ここはひとつ 笑うしかない
At this point, all I can do is laugh
白線のうしろ 立ち上がるんだ
and stand up behind the white safety line!
不覚にも涙がこぼれても
Even if tears should fall in my defeat,
ここはひとつ 笑うしかない
at this point, all I can do is laugh!
いつかキミまで追いつくかな
I wonder if I'll catch up to you someday...
掃いて捨てちゃうほど
Like we're so common we could be swept away,
かわりはいるぞなんて
they say we are easily replaceable.
うっのー！ これどうなの？ おじいちゃんおばあちゃん
No way! What do you think of this, Grandpa and Grandma?
すぐに投げちゃ いけないよね
You shouldn't give up so easily, right?
今も昔も これからずっと
Now and in the past, and from here on out,
かわりの僕はどこにもいない
there is no replacement for me anywhere!
もう ここはひとつ 笑うしかない
Now, all I can do is laugh!
わかりあえるその日が来るまで
Until the day comes when we can truly understand each other!
いつか キミまで 追いつくかな
I wonder if I'll eventually catch up to you.
ふたりの距離は 縮まるかな
I wonder if the distance between us will shrink.
ノドの乾きも 忘れたまま
While still forgetting even my dry throat,
終わらないよ Chase!
It's not over yet, Chase!
キミの代わりは ひとりもいない
There is not a single replacement for you.
キミの代わりじゃ ボクは要らない
If it's just a replacement for you, I don't want it.
不覚にも涙が こぼれても
Even if tears accidentally spill over,
もうここはひとつ 笑うしかない
at this point, there's nothing left to do but laugh.
今も昔も これからずっと
Now, in the past, and forever from now on,
かわりの僕は どこにもいない
there is no replacement for me anywhere.
ああ そうだったのかって きっと きっと
Ah, we will surely, surely say, "Oh, so that's how it was."
わかりあえる その日が来るから
Because the day we understand each other will come.
Chase! 今日もひとつ 笑うしかない
Chase! Today too, there's nothing left to do but laugh.
闇に放り込んだ
Thrown into the darkness,
想い届いていますか
are my feelings reaching you?
浅い夢の覚め際に毎日
Every day as I wake from a shallow dream,
伝う涙の理由はどこから
where does the reason for these trickling tears come from?
きっと戻ってくるよと 頬を撫でる手は冷たくて
Assuring me "I will surely return," the hand caressing my cheek was cold.
ぎゅっと広い背中を 抱きしめた
I tightly hugged your broad back.
謳え 謳え 通い路恋歌 たとえ声はしなくとも
Sing, sing, the path of love song, even if there is no voice.
届け 届け 通い路恋歌
Reach, reach, the path of love song,
愛する人の為 ずっと笑顔で居るから
because I will always wear a smile for the one I love.
淡い日々の思い出に毎日
Every day, in the memories of those fleeting days,
すがる二人の姿は儚げ
the figures of the two of us clinging to each other seem fleeting.
ぎゅっと押さえ続けた 瞳の奥のやさしさが
The kindness suppressed deep in my eyes
ふっと返り咲く刹那に 溢れる心
suddenly blooms again, my heart overflowing in that instant.
止まれ 止まれ 防人恋歌 たとえ声はしなくとも
Stop, stop, the defender's love song, even if there is no voice.
届け 届け 通い路恋歌
Reach, reach, the path of love song,
愛する人の為 ずっと笑顔で居るから
because I will always wear a smile for the one I love.
貴方の為君の為 また出会う日までの約束
For you, for you, a promise until the day we meet again.
どんな思いが馳せようと 笑顔で居よう
No matter what thoughts run wild, let's keep smiling.
遠く 遠く 別れても
Even if we are separated far, far away,
辛い時は歌に乗せて
when times are tough, let it ride on a song.
ずっと待っているよと しがみつく手は震えても
Even if my hands cling and tremble, saying "I will wait forever,"
もっと強く深く深く 抱きしめた
I hugged you even tighter, deeper and deeper.
謳え 謳え 通い路恋歌 たとえ声が枯れても
Sing, sing, the path of love song, even if my voice withers.
笑え 笑え 通い路恋歌 暖かい陽はまだか
Laugh, laugh, the path of love song, is the warm sun not here yet?
ずっと ずっと 謳えるのは 君の声がするから
The reason I can sing forever and ever is because I hear your voice.
届け 届け 防人恋歌 愛する人の為
Reach, reach, the defender's love song, for the one I love,
ずっと笑顔で居るから
because I will always wear a smile.
はい！皆さん、見てますか？
Hi! Everyone, are you watching?
はい、ということでですね、あきちゃんとは「PINK CAT」を。りりかとは「チェイス！チェイス！チェイス！」を
Yes! So, with Aki-chan, I did "PINK CAT." With Ririka, I did "Chase! Chase! Chase!"
そして、防人恋歌をソロで歌わせていただきました！
And then, I got to sing "Sakimuri Renka" as a solo!
はい。まあちょっとね、あの、どうしてこの曲を選んだか、みたいなのはね、まあちょっと、あの…
Yes. Well, as for why I chose this song, well...
その、なんか、世代じゃないんですけど、なんか、この、好きな曲とか、なんか、合いそうな曲、あとは…
It's not quite from my generation, but it's a song I like, one that fits me, and...
みんながね、あの、親しんだ、ポップンといえば、みたいな曲だったり…
a song that everyone is familiar with, like, "when you think of Pop'n, this is it"...
まあ、あの、ピンクローズはね、キーボードマニアの曲なんですけど。
Well, "Pink Rose" is actually a Keyboardmania song, though.
まあでも、みんな好きな曲をちょっと選曲したら、ジャンルはバラバラなのでね。
But anyway, since I chose songs that everyone likes, the genres are all over the place.
とか、防人恋歌は、もう、想い、思い出がありすぎて、やばい…んですけど。
And "Sakimuri Renka" has so many memories for me, it's crazy... but...
あの、好きな曲だったので、ちょっとチョイスさせていただきました。本当にでも、難しかったです。
Since it's a song I love, I chose it. It was really hard, though.
ではですね、えー、今日はですね、あの、衣装、変わりましたけれども。
Now, today... well, my outfit has changed.
今日は、なんとですね、えー、私の、あの、希望で、
Today, surprisingly, at my request,
えー、今回ポップンミュージック ハイ・チアーズで遊べると聞いたんですけど、
I heard we can play Pop'n Music High-Cheery's this time!
え？どこで？どこにあるんでしょう？ちょっと探してみましょうか。
Eh? Where? Where is it? Let's go look for it.
どこ、どこ、どこ、どこ、どこ、どこ、どこ、どこ…
Where, where, where, where, where, where, where, where...
あ、これ…
Oh, this...
これだー！会いたかったー！大好きー！
It's here! I wanted to see you so much! I love you!
え、すごいよ。この技術はすごい技術ですよ。
Wow, this is amazing. This technology is incredible.
皆さん、なかなかあの、VTuberが実機で遊んでいるところを見る機会がね、なかなか無いと思うんですけど。
Everyone, you probably don't get many chances to see a VTuber playing on an actual cabinet.
いや本当に、あの、コナミさんと運営さん、本当にありがとうございます。
Really, thank you so much to Konami and the staff.
今回はね、こちらの可愛い筐体で遊ばせていただくんですけど。
This time, I get to play on this cute cabinet.
あの、皆さんのステージ気づきましたか？こちらですね、なんとスピーカー、このスピーカーとかですね、
And, did you guys notice the stage? Surprisingly, these speakers,
あの、ステージ側にもあるんですけれども、
are also on the stage side as well,
こちらね、合わせていただいたりとかして、もうコナミさんがね、あの、ステージ素材をね、あのご用意してくださったんですよ。
they customized them to match, and Konami prepared the stage assets for us!
いや本当に本当にありがとうございます！
Really, thank you so, so much!
なんか、コナミさんにおんぶにだっこで、本当にすみません。
I'm totally relying on Konami's kindness, I'm so sorry.
私の、今日やりたいことをたくさん、あの、おねがいして、あの、駄目元でお願いしたら、あの、たくさん答えてくださって本当にありがとうございます。
I requested many things I wanted to do today, just in case they'd say yes, and they granted so many of them. Thank you so much.
頭が上がりませんが、あの、せっかくなんでね、早速、ちょっと遊ばせていただこうかなと思います！
I can't thank you enough, but since I'm here, I'd like to play right away!
じゃあ、ちょっと、いいですか？とりあえずハッピーバースデーのとこ叩かせていただいたね。
So, is it okay if I start? Let's tap the Happy Birthday part first.
ポンポンポンポンポンポンポンポン…と、これ、この、画面にね、あの、クラッカーが、映ったりとかするんですけれど。
Pom, pom, pom, pom... and on this screen, you see party poppers going off.
今回は、
This time,
自分のあの、マイカードで、遊ばせていただけるということで。
I get to play using my own card!
あ、ちょっと暗証番号は見せられないんで、ちょっと待ってくださいね。
Ah, I can't show you my PIN code, so please wait a moment.
はい。こうして、ちょちょいのちょいと、入れさせていただきますよ。
Okay. Just a quick entry here, and I'll put it in.
うわ、ポップンミュージックだ！
Wow, it's Pop'n Music!
いつも遊ばせていただいております。お世話になっております。ありがとうございます。
I play it all the time. Thank you for always taking care of me.
ということでですね、今日は、推しを使わせていただきます。
And so, today, I'm going to use my favorite character.
ちょっとね、今回は、あの、ボーカルライブということで、
Well, since today is a vocal live,
あの、ボーカル縛りちょっと3曲をね、選ばせていただこうと思ったんですけど、
I thought about selecting 3 songs with a vocal theme,
今日のラインナップ、えー、3曲は、
today's lineup of 3 songs is...
ポップンミュージックで、一番好きな曲、おとで、まず、遊ばせていただこうかと思います。
I think I'll first play my favorite song in Pop'n Music, "oto".
もうね、大好きなんですよね。
I really love this song so much.
で、ちょっと、ハイパーで、許していただきたいと思います。
So, please forgive me for playing on Hyper difficulty.
今日選ぶ3曲の中で、個人的には一番難しい、
Out of the 3 songs I chose today, personally this is the hardest...
難しいです。
It's really hard.
難しかったんですけど、もう、大好きな曲なので、選ばせていただきました。ボーカルで、この曲選んでいいのかって話なんですけど。
It's hard, but since I love it so much, I chose it. Though I wonder if it's okay to choose this for a vocal category.
いや、この、静かに始まる感じとかね。
Wow, this quiet beginning is so nice.
あの、最後にくる、縦連とかが難しいんですよね。
The vertical streams at the very end are really difficult.
これ、配信バフでフルコンとかできないかな？無理か？
Can I get a full combo with streamer luck? No way?
ちょっと、音ゲーマー、あー、コンボ繋がってるときだけは喋れないと思ったんですけど、切れちゃいましたね。
Ah, rhythm gamers... I thought I shouldn't talk while keeping a combo, but it broke.
あ、右、右手に推し、左手に推し、幸せですね！
Ah, my favorite character on the right, and on the left, I'm so happy!
あー、縦連が苦手なんです。許してください！
Ah, I'm bad at vertical streams! Please forgive me!
Like now, show way!
神曲も...
This god-tier song too...
歌いたかったですね。
I really wanted to sing it.
また、もし何か機会があったら...
If there's ever another opportunity...
歌合わせせてください。
please let me sing it!
どうしてもちょっと後半がグズグズになってしまう。
No matter what, the second half always gets messy.
あーっ！神曲！
Ah! God-tier song!
ここがきつい！
This part is so tough!
はー、なんか取れたかな？大丈夫かな？
Phew, did I manage to clear it? Is it okay?
ああ、一番フレアが一番大好きな曲です。
Ah, it's Flare's absolute favorite song.
これで音を読みます。
Now, let me load the next song.
あー、大好き！
Ah, I love it so much!
あの、推しです。推しのMZDさんです、どちらも。
They're my favorites. Both of them are my beloved MZD.
今日はですね、あの...
Today, you see...
選ぶ3曲のうちの2曲がちょっとMZDの曲なんですけど、
two out of the three songs I chose are MZD tracks,
どうしてもみんなとやりたかったやつもあって、
but there's also one I really wanted to play with everyone.
それを最後にしたいなと思ったんで、ちょっとMZDで挟んじゃうんですけど、
Since I wanted to save it for last, MZD will sandwich them.
今回ちょっとライブでは歌わないのですが、
I won't be singing it live this time, but...
やはりね、あのー、ポップンといえばの中で
as you'd expect, when talking about Pop'n Music,
結構「撫子ロック」じゃないか？っていう方もたくさんいらっしゃったので、
many people suggested "Nadeshiko Rock."
ちょっと撫子ロックを叩かせていただこうかと思います！
So, I thought I'd play "Nadeshiko Rock"!
よろしくお願いいたします！
Wish me luck!
ちょっと速度の調整は大丈夫そうです。
The speed adjustment looks good.
これでいきます！
Let's go with this!
凛として...
Dignified...
咲く花の如く。
Like a blooming flower.
みんなの一番良い曲の一つですね。
It's one of everyone's absolute favorite songs, right?
一番良い曲なんて何曲あったっていいですからね。
After all, you can have as many "best songs" as you want!
そりゃ今日、何回「一番良い曲の一つ」って言ってるでしょう。
I've probably said "one of the best songs" so many times today.
口癖みたいに言ってると思います。
I think I'm saying it like a catchphrase.
そりゃエルフレにもたくさん知ってもらいたいんですよね。
Of course, I want Elfriends to know a lot of them too!
コナミさんのオリジナル曲にはたくさん良い曲があるということを。
I want to show you how many amazing Konami original tracks there are!
トントン、トントントン...
Ton-ton, ton-ton-ton...
つい、歌いがち。
I keep ending up singing along.
ここがね、
This part is...
この後か。
Is it after this?
こういうところ好きですよねー。
You guys love this kind of part, don't you?
咲いた！
It bloomed!
いや、良い曲であり、譜面も良い。
Man, it's a great song, and the chart is great too.
ちょっとなんかお馬さんパカパカみたいな感じで、
It's kind of like galloping horses, clop-clop,
ここ楽しいですよねー。
this part is so much fun!
...の、心！
...heart!
ということで、ギリギリ、スコアが9万点いかないみたいな...
So my score barely missed getting 90,000...
これちょっと悔しいですね。
That's a bit frustrating.
はい、撫子ロック。あ、ニューレコードだそうです。あ、これ自分のカード、マイカードなので。
Yes, Nadeshiko Rock. Oh, it's a new record. Since this is my own card.
はい、ニューレコードだそうです。やっぱ配信バフなんでしょうか。ありがとうございました。
Yes, a new record. Is it the streaming buff? Thank you very much.
最後はですね、
Lastly...
みんなでどうしても叫びたかったあの曲と言ったら、2択だと思うんですけど、
when you think of that song we absolutely had to scream together, there are two options,
ちょっとどうしてもみんなと叫びたい、
but I really, really want to scream this with everyone...
ハンズアップに決まってるじゃないですか！
It's obviously "Hands Up!", isn't it?!
これ知らない方はね、あのカウントのあと、カウントあります。
For those who don't know, there's a countdown.
スリー、ツー、あ、スリー...
Three, two, oh, three...
フォー、スリー、ツー、ワンで「サンライズストリーム」なので、
It goes "Four, three, two, one, Sunrise Stream,"
皆さんで叫びましょう！
so let's scream it together!
叫べるかな？ちょっと45だけど、これ45じゃないんじゃないかってなんか最後がすごい難しいですよね。
Can we scream it? It's Level 45, but actually, I feel like it's harder than 45. The ending is so tough.
速度落としたらごめんなさい。
Sorry if I have to drop the speed.
これ、みんなで叫ぶのが夢だったんですよね
It was my dream to yell this together with everyone.
ゴールドラッシュとね、どっちやろうかなって迷いましたらば、ちょっとセカンドヘブンにしました
I was debating whether to play Gold Rush, but I decided on Second Heaven.
なんか、ボーカル縛りといいながら、2曲英語っていう。あははは
Even though I said it was a vocal-only restriction, both songs are in English. Hahaha.
あ、カウントダウン、一緒にしよう
Oh, let's do the countdown together!
三倍アイスクリーム！
"Somebody scream!" (Three times ice cream!)
みんな、ちゃんとやりました？
Did everyone do it properly?
もう一回ありますからね
There's another one coming up.
あ、正しい歌詞はぜひ調べてください
Oh, please look up the actual lyrics.
息が上がんだ。「三倍アイスクリーム」って言うことが息が上がんだ
I'm out of breath. Saying "Somebody scream" really takes it out of me.
みんなはこの配信を見た後、明日ポップンやりに行きましょうね
After watching this stream, you all should go play Pop'n tomorrow, okay?
人の配信見てるとやりたくなりますからね
Watching someone else play makes you want to do it too.
ちょっと恥ずかしいんですけど手元見られてるの
It's a bit embarrassing having my hands watched.
三倍アイスクリーム！
"Somebody scream!"
急に叫ぶよ
Yelling out of nowhere.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
あ、みんなで「三倍アイスクリーム」が言えて、幸せだ！
Ah, being able to say "Somebody scream" with everyone makes me so happy!
いや、本当にありがとうございます
Really, thank you so much.
あ、待って、でも、3曲終わっちゃった？あ、終わっちゃったよ！
Ah, wait, are the three songs over already? Ah, they're over!
あー、楽しかった！
Ah, that was so fun!
もう、なんか今日ね、あの3曲しか遊べないので、ここで終わしてしまうんですけど... あ、実機プレイはここで終わっちゃうんですけど...
Since I can only play three songs today, it has to end here... Ah, the gameplay portion ends here...
嫌だ！やばい、離れたくない、ポップン！ううう...
No! Oh no, I don't want to leave Pop'n! Nooo...
今日から、もうポップンする！ずっとポップンと離れない！
I'm going to play Pop'n forever! I'm never leaving Pop'n's side!
うう、ポップンしたいよー！
Ugh, I want to play Pop'n!
まあ、ないものはしょうがないか。ちょっと切り替えていきますか
Well, there's no helping what we don't have. Let's switch gears.
まだですね、この後もみんなの好きな、一番いい曲たくさん歌いますので
Actually, after this, I'll be singing a lot of everyone's favorite and best songs.
まぁ、ちょっと楽しみにこの後も観てもらえたら嬉しいなって思います
So, I hope you look forward to watching the rest of the show.
じゃあみんな、次に行くぞ！何の次の曲は？
Now everyone, let's move on! What is the next song?
どはどはどはどは どっ！
Doha-doha-doha-doha-do!
回転頭から ない言語 ハイテンションと 固いテンポ
Nonsense language from a rotating head, high tension and a firm beat,
１先導するジャイケンちから大見解戦法
I guide with rock-paper-scissors to a grand tactics!
回転頭から ない言語 ハイテンションと 固いテンポ
Nonsense language from a rotating head, high tension and a firm beat,
１先導するジャイケンちから大見解戦法
I guide with rock-paper-scissors to a grand tactics!
35＋4÷2すら はじけぬコンパ好き達に
Even simple math like 35+4/2 can't be solved by those party lovers,
あっさり鈍角にねじ込む さばけた音楽鬼は
this level-headed music demon easily screws it into an obtuse angle.
どっから どこまでか わからんハテナが 音わけた理由だ
Not knowing where it starts or ends, this question mark is why the sound split.
どいつと こいつの しゃくりが 垂らした汗ふきな
Go wipe the sweat dripped from everyone's sobbing.
テンダン変化つけた×電波に乗る 大変馬鹿げた発言にゃ
With a sudden change on the radio waves, what a completely ridiculous statement.
グーを作りゃ 人格すら変わるほどに上がる心拍数は
When you make a fist, your heartbeat rises so much that your personality changes.
たっぷりあこぎだが 如意棒を握る力
Though it's plenty greedy, it's the strength to hold the Power Pole.
どうして生まれた時から 続けてきたこの遊び方
Since the moment we were born, we've kept up this way of playing!
回転頭から ない言語 ハイテンションと 固いテンポ
Nonsense language from a rotating head, high tension and a firm beat,
１先導するジャイケンちから大見解戦法
I guide with rock-paper-scissors to a grand tactics!
回転頭から ない言語 ハイテンションと 固いテンポ
Nonsense language from a rotating head, high tension and a firm beat,
１先導するジャイケンちから大見解戦法
I guide with rock-paper-scissors to a grand tactics!
３通りから４通り 本当理より本道理に
From 3 ways to 4 ways, going with instinct over reason.
まかせた義理を梱包し がっつり温厚に
Packing up the obligations left to us, staying completely calm.
とことん交渉する日本馬に
To negotiate thoroughly with Japanese horses...
そんな時そうそうそんな調子
At times like that, yes, that's the spirit.
ぶち壊していくぜ日本道理だば
I'll smash it up, the Japanese common sense!
わー
Wow!
お米の美味しい炊き方、そしてお米を食べることによるその効果。
[Title: How to cook delicious rice, and its effects of eating it]
O!
K.O!
M.E!
RICE!
お米 お米 お米 RICE!
Rice, rice, rice, RICE!
O!
K.O!
M.E!
RICE!
お米 お米 お米 RICE!
Rice, rice, rice, RICE!
スーパー
Super,
パワー
Power,
リラクゼーション
Relaxation!
1) 1合150cc正確無比に計ること
1) Measure exactly 150cc per go.
2) 次に洗いだが直接米にお水を当てず二本指で
2) Next, washing. Do not pour water directly, use two fingers...
3) お水を計りJOIN！するのだがその量米の1.2倍
3) Measure water and JOIN! The amount is 1.2 times the rice.
その後は二時間ほどサディスティック(!)に
After that, soak in water sadistically(!) for 2 hours.
お水に浸して ジャーの電源
Soak in water, and the rice cooker's power...
ON!
陽美(ようび)のような
Like a sunny beauty,
スチーム
steam,
底から
from the bottom,
かき混ぜて
stir it up!
おこめ おこめ おこめ
Okome, okome, okome,
ビタミン ミネラル 食物繊維
vitamin, mineral, dietary fiber!
おこめ おこめ おこめ
Okome, okome, okome,
ああ 食べてどすこい
ah, eat and doskoi!
おこめ おこめ おこめ
Okome, okome, okome,
おすもうさんのPowerをGET
get Sumo wrestler's power!
おこめ おこめ おこめ
Okome, okome, okome,
ああ 抱いてロマンティックにNIGHT FLIGHT
ah, hold me romantically NIGHT FLIGHT!
おこめ おこめ おこめ
Okome, okome, okome,
4) 来屋のあの子をたぶらかそう！
4) Let's seduce that girl from the rice shop!
炊き放題
All-you-can-cook,
食べ放題
all-you-can-eat!
SO I LOVE YOU GET DAZE!
おこめ おこめ おこめ
Okome, okome, okome,
SUPER ENERGY MIRACLE POWER
おこめ おこめ おこめ
Okome, okome, okome,
ああんおこめ
ah, okome,
おお おこめ
oh, okome,
oh, okome!
5) おこめおいしい
5) Okome delicious!
Homesick Pt.2&3
[Title: Homesick Pt.2&3]
真昼と真夜中の間に立つ歌は
The song standing between midday and midnight
真っ白なゲームといて 耳もとではしゃぐ
solves a blank game and frolics by your ear.
パーフェクト 僕らは完璧…なんて 軽い冗談だった
Perfect. We are flawless... that was a light joke.
いつも答えは127の項目
The answer is always the 127th item.
アスファルト蹴りあげたら
If you kick up the asphalt,
EDトランプで決めて
decide it with ED Cards,
急ぎ足で駆け出すのさ 今すぐバスで
and dash out in a hurry, on the bus right now.
そしてホームシック抱えながら人々は目指す
And harboring homesickness, people head on.
行き先はスマートに決めて 願いを叶えたいのなら
Decide your destination smartly, if you want to make your wish come true.
真夏と真冬の間に生まれた歌は保存
The song born between midsummer and midwinter
まったりなカーブ描いて どこまでも進む
draws a lazy curve and moves forward endlessly.
パーフェクト 全ては同じ 似たもの同士だった
Perfect. Everything is the same, we were two of a kind.
いつも答えは同じ音なんだ
The answer is always the same sound.
ソフトロックで暴れたら
If we run wild with soft rock,
トークバックで yeah!
we do it via talkback, yeah!
差し出したルール
The rule presented,
12月のスポーツ
the sports of December,
バジルパスタの試食
and the tasting of basil pasta.
明日の噂話を
Packing tomorrow's rumors
トランクに詰めて
into a trunk,
逆回しでやり直すのさ 悪い性格
we start over in reverse, oh what a bad personality.
それでホームシック語りながら人々は祈る
And speaking of homesickness, people pray.
行き先は満ちあふれてる 誰かが待ちわびるから
The destination is overflowing, because someone is waiting anxiously.
オレンジノイズ 浴びながら
Bathing in the orange noise,
ショートカットで
taking a shortcut,
yeah!
新しいブーム
A new boom,
聞き飽きたフレーズ
a phrase I've grown tired of hearing...
バブルアワーの法則
The law of Bubble Hour.
さあ 明日の噂話を トラックに載せて
Come, let's put tomorrow's rumors on the track,
風に乗せて 薔薇撒くのさ
and scatter them on the wind like roses.
誰の計画？
Whose plan is it?
そしてホームシック
And then, homesick,
笑いながら
with a smile...
人々は迷う
...people are led astray.
行き先はそれぞれさ 皆
Everyone has their own destination.
旅の途中なんだから
After all, we are in the middle of a journey.
風に乗って羽ばたくのは
Fluttering on the wind is...
鳥の計画
...the bird's plan.
行き先はスピードを上げて
Our destination is ahead, pick up the speed.
この先もまだ続くなら
If this path continues on and on,
続くなら
if it continues,
if it continues.
はい、ということで！えー、聴いていただきました曲は、あの、何番目でもいいですか？
Alright! So, those songs you just heard... wait, doesn't matter what track number they are,
ヒップロック、オコメタル、ソフトロック、ということで。
but we played Hip Rock, Okomental, and Soft Rock!
えー、ポルカと1曲、バカタレサーカスで2曲ということで。
We did one song with Polka, and two with the Bakatare Circus.
えー、なんかオコメタルとかでもね、バカタレサーカスでどうしてもやりたかったんですよね。
I really wanted to perform Okomental with the Bakatare Circus!
でもやっぱり、歌の上手いメンバーなんでね。
Since they're all such amazing singers,
あの、皆さん集まって、ソフトロックとかで暴れ散らかしたりしたいなって思ったり、
I thought it'd be great to gather everyone and go wild with some soft rock.
えー、ポルカはね、やっぱりデスロスキーということで、デスロスさんの曲を一緒に歌いたいなと思いましたんで、
And since Polka is a big "Desurosu" fan, I wanted to sing one of Desurosu's songs with her,
このメンバーで、えー、選曲させていただきました！
so I chose this lineup of songs for this group!
ゲストはね、まだまだ、あの、まだまだ、って言ったらあれですね。まだいるので、
We still have... well, it's not "still" many, but we have more guests on the way,
えー、お楽しみに！ということなんですけど、
so please look forward to that!
もうちょっと早いんですけど、あの、先にですね、今回、あの、ちょっとグッズの紹介をさせていただいてもよろしいでしょうか？
Though it's a bit early, could I go ahead and introduce this year's anniversary merch?
えー、また後でですね、あの、グッズの紹介もまた改めて、させていただきます。
(I'll share more details about them again later, too.)
えー、ではですね、いきます。え、不知火フレア 誕生記念2026！
Alright, here we go! Shiranui Flare Birthday Celebration 2026!
えー、早速、えー、ちょっと一つずつ見ていきましょう！
Let's take a look at each of them one by one!
まずは1つ目、
First up, the first item...
マフラータオル！イラストは、ふぁるまろさんに描いていただきました。とっても可愛い！
The Muffler Towel! The illustration was drawn by Farumaro-san. It's so cute!
持ち運びやすいサイズ感なので、ぜひたくさん使ってください。
It's the perfect size to carry around, so please use it lots!
2つ目は、こちら！
Next up is this one!
タンブラー！イラストは、慶十さんに描いていただきました。
The Tumbler! The illustration was drawn by Keiju-san.
今回、なんと！コナミさんに特別許諾をいただいて、あの、筐体の、デザインに、寄せさせていただきました！ありがとうございます。
This time, Konami actually gave us special permission to match it with the arcade cabinet design! Thank you so much!
「ムラクモ M-Z3D」のオマージュイラストなんですけど、
It's an homage illustration to "Murakumo: Arcade Thrill",
のんびり寝転ぶフレアの横には、相棒のうららちゃんと、エルフレも一緒のとっても可愛いイラストとなってます。可愛いすぎ！
and next to a relaxed, lying-down Flare is her partner Urara-chan and an Elfriend. It's such a cute illustration! So adorable!
大容量で、1リットルくらい入って、持ち手も付いてて飲みやすいので、ぜひみんなにも使ってほしいです。
It has a large capacity of about 1 liter, and it's easy to drink from with the handle, so I'd love for everyone to use it!
3つ目は、こちら！
The third item is this!
ぬいぐるみ付きスマホショルダー！お出かけ衣装のぬいぐるみが付いたスマホショルダーです。
Plushie Smartphone Shoulder Bag! It's a smartphone shoulder bag with a plushie of me in my casual outfit.
ケースではないので、様々な機種のスマホが入るんですけど、
Since it's not a hard case, it fits various smartphone models,
全機種対応ではないので、サイズが合わなかった人は、スマホ以外の小物を入れてください。
but it doesn't support every single size. If your phone doesn't fit, you can use it for other small items!
ぜひいろんな場所に連れてってね。
Be sure to take it with you wherever you go!
4つ目はこちら、キャップ！イラストの私とお揃いのキャップです。
Fourth up is the Cap! It's the same cap I'm wearing in the illustration.
今回のコンセプトで、帽子はどうしても外せなかったので、前に出したものとは色とデザインを変えてみました。
A hat was an absolute must for this concept, so we made the color and design different from the one we released before.
どうかな？可愛いかな？かっこいいかな？
What do you think? Is it cute? Is it cool?
シンプルなデザインなので、季節を問わず被れるキャップです。みんなもお揃いにしてくれたら嬉しいな。
It has a simple design, making it a cap you can wear in any season. I'd be so happy if we matched!
5つ目はこちら、シチュエーションボイス！
The fifth item is... the Situation Voice!
フレアと一緒に公園デート。
"A Park Date with Flare."
今回のグッズのイラストに合ったような雰囲気のシチュエーションボイスになってます。みんな、よかったら聞いてね。
It's a situation voice that matches the vibe of the illustrations for this merch lineup. I hope you'll give it a listen!
最後にフルセット。数量限定は直筆メッセージ入りチェキ風ブロマイドカード。通常版は箔押し複製メッセージ入りチェキ風ブロマイドカードが付いてきます。
Finally, the Full Set. The limited edition includes a polaroid-style bromide card with a handwritten message, and the standard edition includes one with a duplicated foil-stamped message.
ふぅ、駆け足だったけど、どれもすごく可愛くて使いやすいと思うので、ぜひみんな買ってもらえると嬉しいです。
Phew, that was quick! But I think they're all super cute and practical, so I'd be so happy if you bought them!
えー、じゃあ次の曲にいこうかな？
Well, shall we move on to the next song?
ゲストはちょっとまだいるので、嬉しい告知とかも残っ、残ってる。
We still have some guests left, and there are still some exciting announcements... waiting!
映ってるかな？
Am I on screen?
みんな、まだ帰らないでね！
Everyone, don't leave yet!
このあとも楽しんでね！
Please enjoy the rest of the show!
追いかけても 追いかけても
Even if I chase after you, even if I chase after you...
するり指をぬける水のように
like water slipping through my fingers.
あなただけに あなただけに
Only you, only you...
見つめられて漂う星の影
can stare at me, a drifting shadow of a star.
夢でもつかまえて
Catch me, even if only in a dream.
流れる雲に思う
I contemplate the drifting clouds,
行き先ないこの心
this heart of mine with nowhere to go.
いつか見た日の明日も
The tomorrow of a day I once saw
青い通り雨
is also a passing blue shower.
色づいた花びら揺らす
Shaking the colored petals,
ぬくもりも 激しささえも
the warmth, and even the intensity.
せつなさの裏側だけを
Only leaving behind the other side of sadness,
残していくくだけの刹那
in just a passing moment.
かなうのなら かなうのなら
If it can come true, if it can come true...
駆け出していきたい風の中
I want to start running into the wind.
あなただけを あなただけを
Only you, only you...
見つめたなら羽ばたく蝶のように
if I gaze upon you, like a butterfly taking flight.
夢ならみせないで
If it's a dream, don't show it to me.
星のない夜に密か
Secretly in a starless night,
巡る季節を忘れて
forgetting the revolving seasons.
いつか来る日の朝を
The morning of a day that will come sometime
隠す涙色
is hidden by the color of tears.
絡む指 艶めく吐息
Intertwined fingers, luscious sighs,
登りつめ落ちゆく心
hearts that reach the peak and fall down.
ひとときのぬくもりさえも
Even that fleeting warmth,
忘れられずにまたひとり
unable to forget, I am alone again.
追いかけたら 追いかけたら
If I chase after you, if I chase after you,
奪い消えてしまう月の影
the shadow of the moon will snatch you away and vanish.
わたしだけに わたしだけに
Only me, only me...
触れられたら煌めく星のように
if you touch me, like a sparkling star.
嘘なら抱きしめて
If it's a lie, embrace me.
届くのなら 届くのなら
If I can reach you, if I can reach you,
明日さえいらない戻らない
I don't even need tomorrow, I won't go back.
離れてても 離れてても
Even if we are apart, even if we are apart,
心焦がす炎はあなただけ
the flame scorching my heart is for you alone.
追いかけても 追いかけても
Even if I chase after you, even if I chase after you...
するり指をぬける水のように
like water slipping through my fingers.
わたしだけが わたしだけが
Only I, only I...
時を止めた闇から手を伸ばす
reach my hand out from the darkness where time has stopped.
かなうのなら かなうのなら
If it can come true, if it can come true...
駆け出していきたい風の中
I want to start running into the wind.
あなただけに あなただけに
Only you, only you...
こころ巡らす はるか朧月
fills my thoughts, the distant hazy moon.
嘘でも抱きしめて
Even if it's a lie, embrace me.
夢なら醒めないで
If it's a dream, don't wake me up.
世界が輝く その瞬間
The moment the world shines,
ちょっとでも 触れたくって
I want to touch it, even just a little.
ごらんよ 幻をのぞいて
Look, peek into the illusion,
空間が重なって 溶けあう
where spaces overlap and melt together.
太陽と月のように
Like the sun and the moon,
時間を超えてはつながる
connecting across time.
大胆不敵な空想の輪郭を追いかけて
Chasing the outline of a daring fantasy,
広がっては飲み込んでいく
it expands and swallows everything up.
世界が輝くその瞬間
The moment the world shines,
ちょっとでも 触れたくって
I want to touch it, even just a little.
ごらんよ 幻をのぞいて
Look, peek into the illusion,
空間を飛び越した
Leaping over space,
未来を追い越すその瞬間
at the very moment we overtake the future,
いつでも こんなものなのさ
it's always like this.
幻をのぞいた僕らの
Our worlds that peeked into the illusion...
世界が 溶けあう
...melt together.
始まりと終わりのように (響き合う音の感情)
Like the beginning and the end... (Emotions of resonating sounds)
記憶を辿ればつながる (混ざり合う)
Connecting as we trace back memories... (Mixing together)
変幻自在に組まれた想像のパズルは
This puzzle of imagination, ever-changingly assembled,
狂おしいほど美しいのだろう
is so beautiful it almost drives me mad.
世界を飛び立つその瞬間 どうしても見せたくて ごらんよ
In that moment we take off into the world, I just had to show you—look!
見慣れない風景に そうさ今駆け出した
That's right, we've started running into unfamiliar scenery now.
未来が不安だった昨日は ちっぽけな何気ない今日なのさ
Yesterday, when the future seemed anxious, has become a tiny, ordinary today.
幻が歪んだ僕らの世界が重なる
Our worlds, where illusions were distorted, now overlap.
本当はずっと世界は僕を待ってた
In truth, the world had been waiting for me all along.
本当はずっと僕も君を待っていたんだ
In truth, I had been waiting for you all along, too.
重なり合った声が遠く響いて届く
Our overlapping voices echo far and wide, reaching out.
聞こえるでしょう
You can hear it, right?
目を開けて物語が始まる時さ
Open your eyes, for it is time for the story to begin.
世界が輝くその瞬間 ちょっとでも触れたくて ごらんよ
In that moment the world shines, I wanted to touch it even a little—look!
幻をのぞいて空間を飛び越した
Peering into illusions, we leaped across space.
未来を追い越すその瞬間 いつでもこんなものなのさ
In that moment we overtake the future, it's always just like this.
幻をのぞいた僕らの世界が溶けあう
Peering into illusions, our worlds melt together.
はい！ということでね、聴いていただきました、「朧」。「ハルモニア」。2曲どうでしたかー？
Alright! And with that, you just heard "Oboro" and "Harmonia." How did you like those two songs?
「朧」は俺の親友アイリスと二人で、なんとダイヤのダンスを踊らせていただきました！めっちゃ難しかった！
For "Oboro," my close friend IRyS and I actually got to perform the dance together! It was super difficult!
どちらもね、大好きな曲なので、ちょっと今回ね、歌えてすごく嬉しかったでした。
Since both of them are songs I absolutely love, I was so happy to be able to sing them this time!
はい、ここまでもですね、盛りだくさんだったんですけど、
Yes, it's already been packed with so much so far,
ちょっと、まだですね、ちょっと嬉しいことがありまして、
but there's still something else to be happy about.
なんとですね、今回、あの、ちょっとビッグな方をちょっとお呼びさせていただきまして、
Believe it or not, we have invited a very special guest today.
BEMANIシリーズで、あの、作曲をしてくださっている方をね、ちょっとお呼びしたんですけど、誰かな？誰かな？と。ちょっと待ってくださいね。
We called up someone who composes songs for the BEMANI series! I wonder who it is? Hold on just a moment.
誰かな？誰が...？
Who could it be? Who...
えっ？だ、いいんですかね？これ、ちょっと、いいですか？えー、あの、
Huh? Is this... is this okay? Is this really allowed? Um,
私が、一番好きな曲と言っていました、えー、音を作っております、wacさんです！くるり？
He created the sound for what I called my absolute favorite song... It's wac-san! *Spin...*
どうも、よろしくお願いします。
Hello, thank you for having me.
あ、よろしくお願いします！今日ありがとうございます！ / はい、ありがとうございます。
Ah, thank you so much! Thank you for coming today! / Yes, thank you.
2Dあったんですね！ / あります。
You actually have a 2D model! / I do.
なんか舌も伸びませんでした？ / 舌はね、
Didn't your tongue just stretch out? / Yes, my tongue...
伸びるんですよ。にょーっと。 / あ、
...stretches out. Like this. / Ah.
結構長い！ / ま、今日はね、これが精一杯なんですわ。
It's pretty long! / Well, today, this is the best I can do.
今日はこれで許して欲しいとのことなんですけど、ちょっとじゃあ自己紹介をしていただいてもよろしいでしょうか？ / あ、ともります。
He asks for your understanding with just this for today. Well then, could you please introduce yourself? / Ah, certainly.
東京都江東区、 / あ、言う、言っちゃっていいんですか？
Koto Ward, Tokyo... / Ah, are you allowed to say that?
コナミアミューズメントよりやってまいりました、新人VTuberのwacです。
...sent directly from Konami Amusement, I'm the rookie VTuber, wac.
よろしくお願いします！ / 困惑。
Nice to meet you! / Confused.
誰？って感じなんですかね？それとも、何？って感じなんですかね？
Are people wondering "Who is this?" or maybe "What is this?"
最近あの、よくね、あのライブリーとかでもやらせていただいているので、
Lately, I've been playing your songs a lot on Livly,
あの、結構うちのリスナーとかも知ってるとか、もともと音ゲーマーさんとかも結構知ってくださって、見てると思うんで、wacさんのことは多分知ってると思います。
so many of my listeners already know you. Plus, I think there are many rhythm gamers watching who definitely know who wac-san is.
「あれ？これもwacさんなんだ！」みたいなの結構後から後から出てくるんですけど、 / そうですね。多くの場合、はい。
People often realize later, "Oh, wac-san made this one too!" / That's right. Quite often, yes.
一旦ちょっとあの、遊ばせていただいた、あの、新筐体の話とか、 / あ、ぜひ。
For now, I'd love to chat about the new arcade cabinet we just played on. / Ah, please do.
あの、12月18とかでしたっけ？
That was... around December 18th, right?
12月18日より順次稼働させていただいております。はい。
Yes, it has been rolling out sequentially starting December 18th.
はい、ぴかぴかポップ君モデル、先ほど遊ばせていただいたんですけど、
Yes, the "Pikapika Pop-kun Model." We got to play on it earlier,
いや、可愛いですね、見た目すごい！ / ですよね！めっちゃ可愛いですよね。
and it looks incredibly cute! / Right? It's super cute.
あの、あと個人的に液晶がめちゃめちゃ明るくて、すごい見やすいです。 / でっかいですしね。
Also, personally, the LCD screen is so bright and easy to see. / And it's huge, too.
そうなんですよ。 / 大きければ大きいほどいいですからね。
Exactly. / Well, the bigger, the better.
そうですね、大きければ大きいほどいいです、何事も。 / はい、何事も。
That's true, the bigger the better, in everything. / Yes, in everything.
あとあの、キャラクターがね、あの昔のキャラクターとかもすごい綺麗に映ったりするの。 / はい。
Also, the older characters look so crisp and beautifully rendered on it. / Yes.
そうですね、皆さんも本当にね
Yes, indeed, and for everyone too...
今回ピカピカポププクモデルが完成するまでにはもう
...until this shiny pop'n model was finally completed,
ポプンスタッフのみんなもそうですけども
not just the pop'n staff but also...
DES-ROW先生や、DJ YOSHITAKAさんや、
DES-ROW-sensei, DJ YOSHITAKA-san,
えー、PONさんや、猫叉Masterさんや、
PON-san, Nekomata Master-san,
TAKAさんや、あさきさんや、
TAKA-san, Asaki-san,
劇団レコードさん、えー、KEIJIくん、タニチュウくん、
Gekidan Record-san, KEIJI-kun, Tanichu-kun...
も、いっぱいです。
...there are just so many people.
筐体を作っていただいた方々もいらっしゃいますし、筐体運んでくださった方々もいらっしゃいますし。
There are people who built the arcade cabinets, and those who transported them as well.
感謝の気持ちで、私、生きております。
I live my life full of gratitude.
この場に立てたのも、皆さんのおかげでございます。
Being able to stand here is all thanks to everyone.
いや、それはあの、本当にこちらが「ありがとうございます」なんですけれども。
No, really, we should be the ones thanking you.
いえいえ、こうして辿り着けたのも、はい、色んな方々のご尽力あってのことでございますので。
No, no, arriving here was only possible due to the efforts of many people.
はい。ということで。なんですけれども、ポップンミュージックのなんか初出し情報とかありますか？
Right. So, do you have any brand-new information about pop'n music?
それはちょっと... / あ、言えない？ / いや、言います。
That's a bit... / Oh, you can't say it? / No, I will.
初出し情報って、何がいいですか？
What kind of new information would you like?
私、一個個人としては、やっぱりMZDの話とか聞きたいんですけども。
Personally, I'd really like to hear about MZD.
MZD？神ですね？ / はい、一番... / 神だから、神ですね。
MZD? The God? / Yes, the most... / Because he's God, he is God.
ですし、結構やっぱ、wacさんって、MZDのなんか半分くらいだと思ってて。
And I kind of feel like wac-san is about half of MZD.
半分？ / で、あとの半分はPONさんなんですよ。
Half? / And the other half is PON-san.
えっとね、厳密に言うと、Mぐらいですね。ZがPONさんで、Dがその他みんな、みたいな。
To be precise, I'm about the 'M'. Z is PON-san, and D is everyone else.
ああ、なるほど、なるほど、なるほど。確かに確かに。
Ah, I see, I see. Indeed, indeed.
なので、ちょっとMZDの話、ちょっともし話せる範囲で聞けたら嬉しいなと。
So, if possible, I'd love to hear what you can share about MZD.
なるほど。MZDの何を知りたいんだい？
I see. What do you want to know about MZD?
キャラ設定とか... / ああ、確か、アマゾン川...
Like his character settings... / Ah, I think the Amazon River...
流域、青基調でしたっけ？ / 流域、青基調ですね。なんでか知らんです。
Basin, blue-themed? / Blue-themed basin, yes. No idea why.
なんで知らんのかい！ / でも、なんか、昔なんか、アマゾンみたいな槍持ってましたよね。
Why don't you know! / But back in the day, he had an Amazon-like spear, right?
カギガですね。 / カギガですね。あれがアマゾンなのかもしれない。違うかもしれない。
That's the Kagiga. / That's the Kagiga. Maybe that was the Amazon element. Or maybe not.
アマゾン要素、そこなんですね。 / うん、多分。
So that's where the Amazon part comes from. / Yeah, probably.
今も青基調に住んでるんですかね？ / 多分。
Does he still live in a blue-themed place? / Probably.
これ、なんか、あれですね。公式さんと話す話...
This feels like... a conversation you'd have with the official developers...
あの、ポップンはね、本当に公式が知らないこといっぱいあるんですよ。
You see, there are actually tons of things about pop'n that the officials don't know.
あ、そうなんですか。 / はい、あの、皆さんの色んな思い出で出来てるので。生半可、公式こそ知らないこともいっぱいあるんで。
Is that so? / Yes, because it's built on everyone's memories. The official developers themselves often don't know.
ああ、後から付いたりとかすることもあるんですかね？曲とかって、曲作ってからキャラクターとか決まるんですか？
Ah, so settings are added later? For songs, do characters get decided after the song is made?
それとも、キャラクターに当てて曲作ったりするんですか？
Or do you write the songs to fit the characters?
おお、なるほど。結構、あの、ケースバイケースっていうか、でもMZDとかは本当に、でもMZDって決まってること多いですよね、やっぱり。
Oh, I see. It's quite case-by-case, but for MZD, MZD is usually decided beforehand.
割と、バージョンの最後の曲だったりすることが多いんで、MZDありきで曲作らなきゃいけないことは多いです。
They are often the final song of a version, so we usually have to write the song with MZD in mind.
特に、このキャラ好きな人が、このキャラに曲作りたいって場合もあります。
Especially when someone who likes a character wants to write a song for them.
ああ、なるほど。
Ah, I see.
新しいね、あの、LivelyにもMZDが出てくると、あの、フレアは期待しているんですけど。出てくると、いいな。
Flare is hoping that MZD appears in the new Lively as well. It'd be great if he did.
あの、なんか、うさ猫の時みたいな、ストーリー結構しっかりみたいなのって、なんか、今後もあったりとかするんですか？
Like, will there be solid stories in the future, like during UsaNeko?
はい、なんか、ストーリー。どうなんですかね？あの、ポップンお好きな方って、そういうストーリー的な、何でしょう。
Yes, a story... I wonder. For people who like pop'n, is that kind of story...
「このキャラ、こんなんだったんだ」みたいなのが分かるのが嬉しいのかな。
...like, is it pleasing to find out, "Oh, this character was like this"?
めっちゃ嬉しいです。本で出してほしいまである。
It makes me incredibly happy. I'd even buy a book of it.
なんか、あの、推しの情報を常に募集しているので、お願いします。
I'm always craving information about my favorites, so please.
マジですか？頼まれちゃいました。大先輩のお願いとあってはね。
Really? I've been requested. Since it's a request from a grand senior...
欲張りに、お願い。 / いいですね。欲張りなのは大切ですよ。
Begging greedily. / That's nice. Being greedy is important.
私、今日実は誕生日なんですけど。 / え、マジですか？おめでとう。誕生日歌いましょうか。
Actually, today is my birthday. / Really? Congratulations. Shall we sing a birthday song?
おめでとう、お誕生日... / これ、今日実装されますか？って。 / ありますか？
Congratulations on your birth... / Will this song be implemented today? / Is there one?
あの、誕生日んで、もし、もしよろしければ、あの、サインとかいただ... 嬉しいなと。
Since it's my birthday, if you don't mind, I'd love to get an autograph...
サイン？そんなん、なんぼでもしますよ。借用書とかじゃなければ、全然、全然書きます、書きます。
An autograph? I'll write as many as you want. As long as it's not an IOU, I'll write it.
今日、あの、二枚ちょっとサイン、あの、カードを用意したんです。好きな方、やっぱり、音ゲーマーといえばカードなんで。借用書じゃないんで。
I've prepared two cards for your signature today. For rhythm gamers, it has to be cards. Definitely not an IOU.
e-amusement passをちょっと二枚用意しました。普通のオーソドックスなやつと、あの、しごとねこのカードをちょっと用意したので。猫なだけに。
I prepared two e-amusement passes. A standard one, and a Shigotoneko one. Since you're a cat.
なるほど。猫だけに。 / どちらでも、どちらにも、サインしてもらえたら嬉しい、ここら辺にきっと、あの、後で出していただくかなと思うので。
I see. Since I'm a cat. / Either one, or both, if you could sign them here, they'll probably show them on screen later.
書きます、書きます。お任せください。 / お願いします、ありがとうございます。 / 上書きします。全てを消し去るように上書きします。
I'll write it, I'll write it. Leave it to me. / Thank you! / I'll overwrite it. I'll overwrite it as if erasing everything.
あわよくば、やっぱり私、あの、BEMANIの楽曲が大好きなので、なんか、もし、いつ、いつ、いつでもいいんですけど、本当に、いつか、カバーとかあったら嬉しいな、とか。
And if possible, I really love BEMANI songs, so if someday—anytime is fine—I'd be so happy to do a cover...
ちょっと、思っ... / おや？ / あ、ちょっと、欲張りすぎました。 / おや？ / ごめんなさい、ちょっと欲張りすぎました。
I was just thinking... / Oh? / Ah, I got a bit too greedy. / Oh? / I'm sorry, I was being way too greedy.
いや、フレアさん、お待たせしました。案件です。
No, Flare-san, sorry to keep you waiting. It's a sponsor deal!
ありがとうございます！ / ここまで溜めて、溜めに溜めて、案件でございます。
Thank you! / Building it up all this way, just to drop the sponsor deal.
案件なんですね。この配信をする時に、「あ、案件なんだな」って思ってた君たち、本当に、本当になかったんですからね。
It really is a sponsor deal! To those watching who thought "Oh, it's just a sponsored stream," we really didn't have one until now!
ありませんでした
No, I didn't.
なんですけど あの 今回
But, actually, this time...
なんと 今wacさんが言ってくださった通り
incredibly, just as wac-san just said,
ちょっと 不知火フレア BEMANIにコラボ
Shiranui Flare's collaboration with BEMANI...
決定しました！ ありがとうございます！
...has been confirmed! Thank you so much!
やったー！
Yay!
やりましたね！
We did it!
やったね！ありがとうございます。めちゃめちゃ嬉しいです。ありがとうございます。
Yes! Thank you so much. I'm incredibly happy. Thank you!
おめでとうございます。
Congratulations!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
なんか ええと どこを触れていいのかなと
So, uh, I'm not sure which part I should mention first.
どのゲームとしましょうかっていう話でですね
About which game we should collaborate with...
え ポップン ポップン ポップン
Eh, Pop'n, Pop'n, Pop'n...
ポップンしたい！
I want to do Pop'n!
まあそうですね
Well, yes.
ポップン さすがにこれでしなかったら わけがわからないんですけど
If we didn't do Pop'n after all this, it wouldn't make any sense,
ここまでして
since we've gone this far.
そうですよね
That's true.
もちろんポップンもなんですけど さらに
Of course Pop'n is included, but furthermore,
今回
this time,
はい
Yes?
SOUND VOLTEXと
SOUND VOLTEX,
やったー！
Yay!
DanceDanceRevolutionと
and DanceDanceRevolution...
おお！
Oh!
3機種でのコラボをさせていただきたいと思っております
...so we will be doing a collaboration across three cabinet models.
すごーい！
Amazing!
これは あの 私の曲が収録されるんですよね？
Does this mean my songs will be included?
それはもちろん
But of course.
もちろん曲ですよ
Of course we mean the songs.
新曲いきましょうよ
Let's make a new song!
新曲！？
A new song?!
新曲
A new song.
実はね ちょっとね この人がいいんじゃないかなと思っているんですよね
Actually, I have someone in mind who I think would be perfect
曲を作ってもらうなら
to write the song for us.
誰なんだろう？
Who could it be?
はい 先ほど
Well, earlier...
MとかZとかDとか言てたんで
you mentioned names like M, Z, or D,
はい
Yes.
今回はそのZにお願いしようかなと思ってます
so I was thinking of asking that "Z" this time.
Zって誰だっけ？
Wait, who was "Z" again?
ええと Z Z Z誰だったっけ？
Uh... Z... Z... Who was Z again?
ポですね ポ ポです
It's "Po". Yes, "Po".
ポンです P-O-N ポンという
It's PON! P-O-N, PON,
ポンさん！
PON-san!
なかなかいい曲を書く子がいるんですよ ポップンミュージック
who is a really talented composer for Pop'n Music.
ほえー
Oh!
先ほどそうですね フレアさん MZDの曲が好きって言ってましたけど
Earlier, you mentioned you like MZD's songs,
まあ3分の1くらい作ってて
well, PON actually composed about a third of them,
最近結構MZDの曲いっぱいまた作ってますし
and has been writing a lot of MZD songs lately too.
それ本人も歌うし あの 女性ボーカリストの曲もいっぱい書いてるような
He also sings them himself, and writes a lot of songs for female vocalists.
PONさんが
That PON-san is...
私は あの wacさんとPONさんが あの 一番好きなんですよね
Actually, wac-san and PON-san are my absolute favorites.
マジっすか？ありがとうございます
Really? Thank you so much.
ちょっと涙が出ちゃいそう
I'm almost in tears.
恥ずかしくて隠れちゃいます
I'm too embarrassed, I'm going to hide.
あ 隠れ…出てきてください
Ah, hide... Please come back out.
ありがとうございます 楽しみに待ってます
Thank you so much! I can't wait.
せっかくなんで あの 来て wacさん来ていただいたから
Since you've gone to the trouble of coming here, wac-san,
あの なんか よかったら あの
if you'd like, maybe...
実機に収録される楽曲を
...the song that will be included in the game cabinets,
wacさんと一緒に なんかやりたいなと思うんですけど 歌います？
I'd love to perform it together with you, if possible. Would you sing it?
いいでしょう！
Sure, why not!
せっかくなんで あれですね 2人だけでやりましょう
Since we're here, let's do it with just the two of us.
あの ピアノと歌だけで
Just the piano and vocals.
え！
Eh?!
いいですか？
Is that okay?
え めちゃめちゃ嬉しい 緊張します
Wow, I'm incredibly happy, but so nervous!
めちゃめちゃ緊張します 自分も
I'm incredibly nervous too.
頑張ります！頑張ります！
I'll do my best! I'll do my best!
頑張ります 実はね 練習してます 自分 このために
We'll do our best. Actually, I've been practicing for this.
楽しみ
I can't wait to hear it.
聞いていただきたい ぜひ
I'd really love for you to listen to it.
はい では えー フレア
Yes! Now then, this is Flare...
wacさんによる 聴いてください
...and wac-san. Please listen to...
「僕の飛行機」
"My Airplane."
どこまで飛べるかを
To find out how far we can fly,
確かめに僕ら旅に出る
we set off on a journey.
夢は尽きることを忘れて
Forgetting that dreams eventually end...
草原を
...across the grassy plains...
駆け抜けて行ったけど
...we ran.
幼い憧れと
With childhood longings,
ほどけた指切り
and broken pinky promises...
絆にする
...turned into bonds.
逃げ出せないから ただ空を見てた
Unable to escape, I just stared at the sky.
かっこ悪いから ウソをついた
Because I was embarrassed, I told a lie.
白いノート 1枚破って
Tearing a page from a blank notebook...
今日の日付と さようなら
...with today's date and a farewell,
託した紙飛行機
I entrusted them to a paper airplane.
風に乗って 舞い上がって
Riding the wind, soaring high,
蒼く溶けた
it dissolved into the blue.
旅立ちの歌を背に
With a departure song behind me,
白い軌道追いかけて
chasing after that white vapor trail...
ここで見た 淡い夢も
...even the faint dream I had here,
翼にして
I will turn into wings.
いつか誰かに 届いてくれる？
Will it reach someone someday?
僕の飛行機
My airplane.
乗りこんだ汽車が
If the train I boarded
見上げてた空へ
leads to the sky
続くなら
I looked up at...
夢をみてた遠い日々に
In those distant days I spent dreaming,
取り残されてる記憶は
the memories left behind
まだあの空を覚えているから
still remember that sky.
絡み合って もつれ合って
Intertwined, tangled together,
やがて一人
eventually, we were left alone.
さよならの歌 胸に
With a song of farewell in my heart,
約束を数えてるけど
I count our promises, but...
ここで見てた淡い夢も
even the faint dreams I had here,
翼にして
I'll turn into wings.
きっとどこまでも追いかけると
I'll surely chase after you, no matter how far,
信じてる
I believe.
風に乗って 舞い上がって
Riding the wind, soaring high,
蒼く溶けた
melting into the blue,
あの紙飛行機は
that paper airplane,
誰の手に届いただろうか
I wonder whose hand it reached.
夢が覚めて
Even when I wake from this dream
僕が空に還る時も
and return to the sky,
ずっと変わらずに
always unchanged,
僕は君の中に生きている
I will live on inside of you.
おおー！アレンジすごい！いや、ありがとうございました！
Wow! The arrangement is amazing! Thank you so much!
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
めちゃめちゃ貴重な経験をさせていただき…
I've had such an incredibly valuable experience...
こちらこそ。はい、ありがとうございました。
The pleasure was mine. Thank you very much.
はい、ありがとうございました。wacさんでした。
Thank you so much. That was wac-san!
はい、作ってるのはこの猫です。
Yes, the one who composed it is this cat.
一言、最後にあります？
Do you have a final word before you go?
いや、もう本当にあの、この度は素晴らしい機会をいただきまして、こちらこそありがとうございました。
No, really, thank you so much for giving me such a wonderful opportunity.
ありがとうございました。
Thank you so much!
はい、今後ともぜひポップンミュージック、BEMANIシリーズをよろしくお願いいたします。
Yes, please continue to support Pop'n Music and the BEMANI series.
よろしくお願いします！
Please support them!
はぁー！いや本当に嬉しいですね。大好きな「僕の飛行機」をwacさんと一緒にお届けしました。
Sigh... I'm really so happy. I performed my favorite "Boku no Hikouki" together with wac-san.
アレンジバージョンどうでしたか？めちゃ凄かったですよね！
How was the arranged version? It was absolutely amazing, wasn't it?
wacさんからこう、ご提案いただきまして、今回アレンジバージョンで歌わせていただきました。
wac-san suggested this to me, so I sang the arranged version this time.
めちゃめちゃ嬉しい。もうなんか、思い残すことがない…
I'm so incredibly happy. I feel like I have no regrets left......
あ、まだ思い残すことはたくさんある！ね、だってコラボとかもありますからね！
Oh, wait, I still have plenty of regrets left! Yes, because there are still collaborations and stuff!
あ、でですね。あの、ここで新曲が出ます！
Oh, and also, a new song is coming out now!
なんか、ぬるっと出てきたんですけど、これさっき言ってた、wacさんが言ってた「ポンさんの」とかじゃなくて
It kind of slipped out naturally, but it's not the "Pon-san's" one wac-san was talking about...
私個人のあの、新曲が出ます！「Silent Flame, Never Fade」という曲になります。
...it's my own personal new song! The song is titled "Silent Flame, Never Fade".
で、作詞作曲がですね、fripSideさんの八木沼悟志さんに、あの、作っていただきました。
And the lyrics and composition were done by Satoshi Yaginuma-san of fripSide.
配信の後、MVも出ますので、え、お楽しみに！ということなんですけども。
After the stream, the MV will also be released, so please look forward to it!
こちら、デジタルリリースはこの後、0時からとなっております。
The digital release will be available from midnight tonight.
そしてですね、なんと、え、この新曲「Silent Flame, Never Fade」が
And also, surprisingly, this new song "Silent Flame, Never Fade"...
ポップンミュージック、ダンスダンスレボリューション、サウンドボルテックスの3機種になんと収録されます！すげえ！
...will be included in three games: Pop'n Music, DanceDanceRevolution, and Sound Voltex! That's incredible!
マジか！
For real?!
なんか、感想って言われたけど、「マジか」しかちょっと出てこないんですけど。
They asked for my thoughts, but all I can say is "For real?!"
はい、ありがとうございます。
Yes, thank you very much.
このほかの詳細もですね、生誕グッズも含めて、最後に改めてお知らせしますので、え、おまちください。
I will announce more details, including the birthday merchandise, at the very end, so please wait for that.
ではですね、早速今お知らせしました新曲をですね、まぁ聞きたいと思いますので、お披露目しようかなと思います。
Now, I'd like to perform the new song I just announced, so I will reveal it now.
それでは聞いてください。「Silent Flame, Never Fade」。
Please listen to: "Silent Flame, Never Fade".
静かに揺れ続ける焰
A flame that quietly keeps flickering
名もなき道照らし出す
lights up the nameless path.
失くしていた未来さえ
Even the future that I had lost...
いまあなたと新たな明日を刻んだ
...now together with you, I carve out a new tomorrow.
いくつもの夜を超えて
Overcoming countless nights,
紡いできた自分らしさ
the uniqueness I have spun,
選択したその全てが
every choice that I've made
私をまた突き動かす
drives me forward once again.
強がってた訳じゃなくて
It wasn't that I was trying to act tough,
止まることが怖かったよ
I was just afraid of stopping.
迷っていたあの日もきっと
Those days when I was lost
今のチカラになってるよ
surely have become my strength now.
一人きりだと思っても
Even if I think I'm all alone,
気づけばそこにある笑顔が
before I know it, the smiles around me...
私といつも一緒に歩いてくれてた
have always been walking right beside me.
その意味 そのチカラ
That meaning, that power...
絶対に離さない！
I will never let it go!
加速していくこの想いは
This accelerating passion
いま翼を纏い出す
now begins to clothe itself in wings.
私が私でいれる
Just being able to be myself...
それだけで十分だから
is more than enough for me.
逃げないって決めたのは
The reason I decided not to run away...
強くあったからじゃない
isn't because I became strong.
私を呼ぶその声と
With the voice that calls my name...
重ね合った 信じる世界の明日を
and the overlapping tomorrow of the world I believe in...
傷つくこと躊躇ってた
I hesitated to get hurt,
立ち止まったこともあった
and there were times I stood still.
そんな時にこの背中を
At those times, this back of mine...
押してくれたその眼差し
was pushed forward by that gaze.
迷いながら選んだ道
The path I chose while wandering,
間違いさえ真実だと
even the mistakes are a truth.
その焔は闇を照らして
That flame shines through the darkness,
私に正しさをくれた
giving me the righteousness.
張り裂けそうに痛んでも
Even if it hurts enough to tear me apart,
この胸に刻んだ勇気が
the courage carved into this chest...
私をいつも支えてくれていたから
has always been supporting me.
今ここに感じ合う
Now, here, we feel each other—
あなたと私の夢
your dream and mine.
燃え尽きることの無い夢は
A dream that will never burn out
この大空に羽ばたいて
flies high into this vast sky.
涙さえも輝かせ
Making even my tears shine,
誰かの夜を照らしたい
I want to illuminate someone's night.
逃げないって決めたのは
The reason I decided not to run away...
強くあったからじゃない
isn't because I became strong.
静かな焔を抱いて
Embracing a silent flame,
何度だって立ち上がれること知ったから
because I learned that I can rise up again and again.
たとえ世界が色を失くし
Even if the world loses its color
光が遠ざかっても
and the light fades away,
この名に刻む焔は
the flame carved into this name...
あなたと私を繋いで
will connect you and me.
逃げないって決めたのは
The reason I decided not to run away...
強くあったからじゃない
isn't because I became strong.
私を呼ぶその声と
With the voice that calls my name...
重ね合った 信じる世界の明日を
and the overlapping tomorrow of the world I believe in...
この後詳細お知らせ！まだ帰らないでね！
[Notification: Details after this! Don't go home yet!]
不知火フレア2026 BEMANI楽曲3D LIVE、見てくれて本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for watching Shiranui Flare 2026 BEMANI Song 3D LIVE!
今回のこのコラボは本当に生誕ライブを企画する際に最初から決まっていたものではなく
This collaboration wasn't actually planned from the very beginning when organizing this birthday live show,
みんなが声を上げて盛り上げてくれたから叶った案件なので
but it became a reality because everyone voiced their support and built up the hype,
改めて皆さんに御礼を言わせてください。本当にありがとうございます！
so let me express my gratitude to all of you once again. Thank you so much!
よし！気になる不知火フレア BEMANIコラボ、コラボの詳しい...
All right! The exciting Shiranui Flare BEMANI collab... For the details of the collaboration...
いないよ？発表していくよ。
No one's left? Let's get to the announcements!
改めて、今回コラボするゲームは...
To recap, the games we are collaborating with...
ポップンミュージック、ダンスダンスレボリューション、サウンドボルテックスの3機種です！
...are pop'n music, DanceDanceRevolution, and SOUND VOLTEX!
この3機種に、先ほど披露した「Silent Flame, Never Fade!」が収録されます！
The original song "Silent Flame, Never Fade!", which I just performed, will be added to these three games!
ご覧の日時からプレイすることができますので、お楽しみに！
You can play it starting from the dates shown on screen, so look forward to it!
さらにさらに！不知火フレアが歌う、BEMANIシリーズのカヴァー楽曲の収録も決定しました！
What's more, BEMANI cover songs sung by me, Shiranui Flare, will also be added!
収録楽曲、収録機種、収録日時については、ご覧の通りです！
The playable songs, models, and dates are as shown on screen!
そして！まだまだ終わりません！
And that's not all!
BEMANIアーティストとの、コラボ新曲の制作が決定しました！
A new collaboration song with a BEMANI artist has been confirmed for production!
続報は、ポップンミュージック公式Xで発信予定ですので、ぜひチェックしてみてください！
Further updates will be posted on the official pop'n music X account, so keep an eye out!
さあ、ここからは、各機種ごとのコラボ内容をまとめてご紹介していきます。
Now, let's take a look at the details of the collaboration for each game!
ポップンミュージックでは、なんと不知火フレアがポップンキャラとして登場しちゃいます！
In pop'n music, Shiranui Flare will actually appear as a playable pop'n character!
さらに、ゲームをより楽しくプレイできる、コラボカスタマイズアイテムも登場します！
Also, custom collaboration items that make playing even more fun will be available!
詳細は追って、公式Xにて発表予定なので、お見逃しなく！
Details will be announced later on the official X account, so don't miss it!
ダンスダンスレボリューションでは、ゲーム画面を自分好みに変更できるプレミアムカスタマイザーとして、コラボアイテムが登場予定です！
In DanceDanceRevolution, collaboration items will appear as a Premium Customizer to let you customize your screen!
サウンドボルテックスでは、これまでホロライブメンバーも登場してきたネメシスクルーに、不知火フレアも新加入します！
In SOUND VOLTEX, Shiranui Flare will join the Nemesis Crew, where other Hololive members have also appeared!
さらに、カスタマイズアイテムとしても登場予定です！
She is also scheduled to appear as a customization item!
こちらも詳細は追って、公式Xにて発表していくので、忘れずにチェックしてね！
Details for this will be released on the official X account as well, so don't forget to check!
ということで、今回はフレアがずっと愛してやまない、BEMANIシリーズのオリジナルソング縛りのライブがしたいというね...
So, this project started because I wanted to do a live show featuring only original songs from the BEMANI series, which I love so much...
...完全にフレアのやりたい放題ライブの企画だったわけなんですが...
...so it was completely a self-indulgent live show planned just for me...
そこから、こんなにたくさんゲームに実装されてしまうなんて、いまだにちょっと現実味がありませんが...
...but for all of this to be implemented in the games because of that, it still feels so unreal...
長年愛しているBEMANIユーザー様も、末永く今後ともBEMANIシリーズのことをよろしくお願いします。
To all the BEMANI players who have loved the series for years, please keep supporting it for a long time to come.
あ、不知火フレアもよければよろしくお願いします。
Oh, and please support Shiranui Flare as well if you'd like.
ということで、音ゲーマー特有の親目線ですが...
And, though it's kind of like a proud parent's perspective unique to rhythm gamers...
すでに遊んでいるエルフレはもちろん、まだ始めてないエルフレも、これを機に遊んでもらえたら嬉しいです！
...of course I hope current Elfriend players, and even those who haven't started yet, will take this chance to play!
そして新曲もね、このあとMVが公開されるのと...
Also, for the new song, the music video will be released after this...
0時にはリリースもされるので、たくさん聴いて、観てくれると嬉しいです！
...and it will be digitally released at midnight, so I hope you listen to and watch it a lot!
あとグッズ！今回ですね、少し早めにお知らせさせていただいたので、さらっと振り返るね。
Now, for the merchandise! Since we announced them earlier, let's do a quick recap.
マフラータオル、タンブラー、ぬいぐるみ付きスマホショルダー...
The muffler towel, tumbler, smartphone shoulder bag with a plushie...
...キャップ、シチュエーションボイス、フルセット！
...cap, situation voice, and the full set!
どれも可愛くて使いやすいと思うので、ぜひお仕事だったり、お出かけとか...
They're all cute and practical, so you can use them at work, going out...
...スポーツとか、ゲームセンターとか行ったりとか、何でも使ってみてください！
...playing sports, going to the arcade, or whatever you like!
グッズの販売はこのあと21時半からなので、数量限定も、たくさん用意しているのもあるので、焦らずにね。
The merchandise goes on sale at 9:30 PM. We have prepared plenty of stock, even for the limited edition, so don't rush!
裏話なんかは、また改めてお話しさせてください。
I'll share some behind-the-scenes stories on another occasion.
今回は思いもよらないことが本当にたくさん起きて...
So many unexpected things happened this time...
運営さんも、KONAMIさんも、エルフレのみんなも、感謝の気持ちでいっぱいです！
I'm full of gratitude toward management, KONAMI, and all the Elfriends!
本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
さあ、明日はゲームセンターに行っちゃう？行っちゃう？ね、一緒に行こう！
Well then, are you going to the arcade tomorrow? Are you? Hey, let's go together!